♪ In the not-too-distant
future--next Sunday, A.D.-- ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked
at Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job cleaning up
the place, ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn'’t like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'’ll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ He'’ll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ Then we'’ll monitor his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can'’t control ♪
♪ When the movies begin or end ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll-call-- ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you'’re wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
- ♪ La-la-la ♪
- ♪ Then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ "It'’s just a show,
I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000." ♪
- Ohh.
- 30 seconds to commercial sign.
- Morning, Crow.
- I'’m Servo.
- I mean Tom Servo.
- Morning.
- Hey, good morning
breakfast clubbers.
Heh, hey. How you doing?
Hey, here'’s a little
morning poem.
Birdie with a yellow bill
Hopped upon my window sill
Cocked his shining eye and said
What'’s for breakfast, Grandma?
- Oh, I hate morning bots.
- Ugh.
- Commercial sign in 15 seconds.
- That reminds me.
My name is Joel.
And I'’m the subject of a bizarre
movie watching experiment.
And now I guess so are you.
We'’re expecting a call
any minute
from the quasi-evil overlords
who shot me into space.
So stick around.
- Yeah, if Crow'’s chipperness
doesn'’t kill us first.
- Hey!
- Commercial sign in five,
four, three, two--
commercial sign now.
- Keep your head up, guys.
- Stick around.
We'’ll be right back.
All right. And...
- There'’s the lady.
- Okay. I'’m busted.
All right, double or nothing.
Okay. Little game of chance.
- Find the--
- There.
- They'’re calling.
Come in, sirs.
- Come in, Joel, my little 3.98
all-you-can-eat space buffet.
- Hey, sirs, what'’s up?
You know what'’s up.
Make with the invention
exchange, pasty boy.
- Hey, sirs, I'’m ready.
Hey, Cambot,
bring it in a little bit.
This is a thing I invented
for people who are studying
to be cartoon characters,
you know,
It'’s like when a beautiful woman
comes by you in the cartoons,
you go like this.
Or like this.
Kind of like that.
And then you get into
your upper level courses.
And you can do the walk by.
She'’s great.
And then followed by.
See. What do you think?
- Not bad, not bad.
- Now, get an eyeful
of our little wonder.
- Yes, we'’ve been dealing
with genetic mutations
since you were in short pants.
- And we finally applied
our principles to carnival food.
We came up with cotton candy
that scream when you bite it.
- May I?
- Enjoy.
- Ow! That'’s my head! Ow!
- Well, what do you think of
that, Joel-arini?
- You'’re toying with God'’s
blueprint, that'’s what I think.
- Yeah!
- Thank you.
- Well, Joel, we'’ve got another
cinematic compost pile for you
called The Slime People.
- Oh, it'’s scabby and bumpy
and absolutely hideous.
- But first,
another space frolic
with our bullet-headed friend,
Commando Cody.
- Enjoy.
[Buzzing, Screaming]
- You know, I just don'’t think
that cotton candy thing
was legitimate.
- I don'’t know.
It look pretty real.
- A new character--Commando Cody
in Radar Men from the Moon.
[Music plays]
- It is sort of hypnotic,
isn'’t it?
- Hip, not ick.
[Humming to music]
- I wish the scientists would
install one of those oil things.
- Oh, the oil and water things?
- Hills of Death.
The production company has
installed a small piece
of information for you
the readers to read
as if you cared about what
happened in the last segment.
♪ Something new is coming
to town ♪
♪ And George the milkman
is bringing it '’round ♪
- You think we'’ll meet them
on the road?
- Of course you will.
You did last week.
- Truck.
- Car.
- If I remember right.
Cody'’s about to collide
with the evil Good Humor Man'’s
ice cream car of death.
- Bet you an ROKP they jump.
- There it is.
- It'’s going to crash into us!
- Bail out!
- Oh, did I say jump?
I meant swerve.
- Oh, great,
that was on my MasterCard.
- Here'’s the payroll.
- I said jelly rolls
not payrolls.
- Doh!
- Retik calling Croft.
- Uh, Mr. Retik,
line one, please.
- The donuts are here, sir.
They'’re fluffy and delicious.
- I was just about to call you
to report that we are about
to put our ray gun
into operation again.
- I have another mission
for you first.
Do you have an atomic bomb
strong enough
to start a volcanic eruption
in the Mt. Alta crater?
- Not on me.
- ...in that mountainous area
would do very little damage.
- On the contrary, it will do
a great deal of damage.
The present atmospheric
conditions on earth
indicate that the eruption would
cause torrential rains.
And the resulting flood should
seriously disrupt transportation
and defense measures.
- An excellent idea.
We shall carry it out at once.
- That'’s why he'’s the boss.
- Then start an intensified
campaign with the ray gun.
Earth'’s defenses must be
completely broken down
before we can risk
an invasion from the moon.
Yes, your Excellency.
- What a wing nut.
- Oh, man you guys are gonna
love this one.
- You heard the orders.
Charter a plane and drop
one of our atomic bombs
into the Alta crater.
- Nature will do the rest.
- Okay. When do we do it?
- At once.
I will get you the bomb.
- It'’s right over here
by the toaster oven.
- This one'’s called
"The Baby Boy."
- Joel, what'’s the matter
with these guys anyway?
I mean, they'’re ready
to sell their home planet
for some money.
- Well, they just don'’t have
any real home planet pride.
- You think they have wives
and families?
- Yeah.
- No, I bet they sold them too
to pay for those nice suits.
- You know, the Cessna Skyhawk
is usually your best choice
for bombardiering missions.
- Here it goes.
- Good shot.
Right in the wading pool.
Krakatoa east of Java.
Bentonville east of Monsey.
Competition keen as nation'’s
best vie for top honors.
- Hey, you ho-daddys. Surf'’s up.
- Oops, the water broke.
- That'’s a bridge under
troubled water.
- They'’ll be surfing in Boston.
- Local high school
grabs corn crown.
Bluerth to build beet palace.
- If the moon men did start
that eruption,
they certainly got results.
- You'’ve got to admire
them moon men.
- That volcano'’s been dead
for years.
Took quite a blast
to get it going again.
An atomic bomb dropped
from a plane
would seem to be
the only answer.
- He'’s right for $200.
- Oh, finally I come in and you
two aren'’t fighting anybody.
- How'’d you make out?
- Like a bandit.
- The second airport I checked
had chartered a plane
on the day of the eruption
to two men,
answering to the description
of Graber and his pal.
- Then we'’re right. They'’re
the ones who bombed the volcano.
- Looks like it.
- Yes, but that doesn'’t help us
catch them.
Couldn'’t you get a line on them?
- The names and addresses
they gave are phony.
But I did get one break.
The airport manager borrowed
these matches from Graber
and forgot to get them back.
- Al'’s Cafe.
That might do us some good.
- Especially if you'’re hungry.
- And if we'’re lucky,
they might be regular customers.
So let'’s go
and look the joint over.
- Right.
- Crooks are always dropping
obvious clues like that.
It'’s really a desperate cry
for help, you know.
- Oh, Al'’s Cafe,
they do a really nice job there.
Blue plate special
that'’ll really make
your pelt stand on end.
- ...but I don'’t know their
names or anything about '’em.
- Well, if they show up,
I wish you'’d call me.
- Sure,
I'’ve got nothing better to do
with my miserable life
than call you.
- I sure will, Mr. Cody.
- Thanks.
- Hey, how convenient.
Everybody dance!
- They'’re all short order
crooks.
- Uh, gentlemen,
I can seat you immediately.
- You know, dropping those
matchbooks all over town
really helped business.
- Well, this is my lucky day.
- He'’d like that to go.
- Right in the kidney beans.
- Right in the cream corn.
- Right in the liver and onions.
- Right in the Salisbury steak.
- That'’s it. Next time I talk,
I let this
do the talking for me.
- You or the cops try to follow
us, I'’ll give it to him quick.
- Give what?
- The bill.
- Oh, put that on my tab.
- Hey, isn'’t anyone going
to drive?
- All right, Ted, we'’re going
to Barney'’s Chili Snack
and do the same thing.
- Wake up, Cody.
You owe me $400.
- Cough up.
- They took your pal, Mr. Cody.
- You gonna call the cops?
- I don'’t dare to.
They'’d kill him sure.
- Oh, I'’m stuffed.
That'’s the best progressive
dinner I'’ve ever had.
Martha'’s Jell-O mold
was out of this world.
- Get your hand off my knee.
- Huh?
- Good reaction time.
- Hey, give them a break.
They'’re trashed.
- Come and get me.
I'’m a fuzzy little fuzzy rabbit.
I'’m being bad.
You have to spank me.
I'’ve been bad, bad, bad, bad.
- Soon as he can get to a phone,
he'’ll have the cops
on our trail.
- The bunny trail.
- The road to Clark Mountain
is just up ahead.
We'’ll hide out there until
Qua can send us another car.
- Come back,
the bunny'’s still in the bushes.
- That'’s an electric razor,
you idiot.
- Come in, Graber.
- We just had a run in
with Cody again.
Our car is hot.
We'’ll have to have another one.
- We want one with factory air.
We'’re heading up
to Clark Mountain.
We'’ll stop before we get
to the top and wait there.
- Very well,
I'’ll have another car out there
as soon as possible.
- Did dad sound mad
about the car?
- Meanwhile back
at the Cody Institute
for Naughty Little Bunnies...
- What do you think
they'’ll do to him?
- It'’s hard to tell.
They'’ll certainly hold them--
[Phone rings]
Cody laboratory?
Ted, where are you?
- In a gas station
on highway 17.
I jumped out of the car
and gave them the slip.
- Good work. Now we can go after
them. Where are they heading?
- They were going up
the Clark Mountain road.
- I'’ll use the rocket suit
and try to find them.
- Okay. Don'’t worry about me.
I'’ll bum a ride back to town.
- I'’m fine. You guys just go
to the movie without me.
- Phone the police and tell them
to block the highway
on the other side
of the mountain.
- Right.
- Hello, police?
Block the mountain on the other
side of the highway.
- Police headquarters.
- Nipple one, nipple two.
And hop, hop, wah!
[Humming]
- Hey, wait a minute.
I'’m flying.
- Hey!
- Meanwhile
in the hills of death.
- He acts like a bunny,
and we fall to pieces.
What kind of thugs are we?
- Hey, Daley.
Quit worrying. Car can'’t get
here for a while yet.
- Traffic on outbound 72
is heavy going
into spaghetti junction.
And wait a minute.
Well, there'’s some little,
tiny ants on the cross town.
Oh, those are cars.
- Ooh, my arches.
Oh, I got to go.
Let me find a place.
When will I learn.
I should always go before I fly.
- Steve, have you ever
really looked at a squirrel?
I mean, really up close.
- Hey. Hey, it'’s Cody.
- I sure wish we had
one of those flying suits.
- You know, there'’s nothing
like being in a gunfight
with 600 pounds of high-test
nitro rocket fuel on your back.
Time to get out of here.
Follow me. Keep low.
- Serpentine!
Back and forth. Back and forth.
Oh. Oh. Oh. Ah.
- Uh-oh, this isn'’t good.
I'’ve seen good before,
and it didn'’t look like this.
- When Cody gets here,
give yourself up.
Try not to get too close to him.
- Wet your lips.
- Don'’t argue.
- And straighten that tie.
- Time little rabbit.
- Don'’t move.
- Montana looks long.
He'’s got a man open.
Oh, pass. Pass interference! Oh!
Just in time.
Coo.
Sort of looks like
I Dream of Genielettering.
- Yep. That'’s right.
- Hi. I'’m a slime person.
And this is our story.
Come on along with me.
Sure, we'’re not much to look at.
But we'’s good people.
- Sure.
You think you have troubles.
But when you live
in the bowels of the city,
you can'’t go running and
complaining to your landlord.
- Nice rock garden.
Oh, it'’s his back. Ew.
- I noticed that during the most
troublesome times in my life,
Lord, there were only
one set of footprints.
- Oh, look.
They'’re serving hors'’dourves.
- Corpse kabobs.
- The Slime People--
the story of Hollywood
in the early days.
[Music plays]
- Play it, Jackson.
- Hey, Boyce and Hart.
I wonder if they did the music.
- Underwater photography
by Jimmy Crab.
- Filmed in mucous vision.
- You know, I think
this is also the lettering
in The Bionic Woman.
- Was it boring bold?
- Well, they had the technology.
- Airport 77--
the other guy'’s story.
- Easy now. Easy.
- Penny, this is Sky King.
- Hey, where'’s the guy
on the stick?
- The Piper Cub,
figurehead of an empire.
- L.A. controls. Come in, L.A.
Do you read me?
- Oh, he'’s in L.A.
That explains the bad air.
- Why'’s he talking
in to a shaver?
- This is 7557 Tango.
Need L.A. visibility reading.
Can anyone read me? Over.
- Santa Barbara control
to Tango.
Santa Barbara control to Tango.
Do not attempt landing.
Repeat, do not attempt landing
at Los Angeles.
- Takes two to tango.
- Get out of L.A. immediately.
Get out of L.A. area.
Divert north. Get out of L.A.
Divert north.
- Oh, brother, this must be
the granddaddy of all storms.
- Oh, it'’s a granddaddy
all right, dude.
Really gnarly fog happenin'’.
- Easy now.
- Feels like we'’re in the plane.
- LAX just isn'’t
the same anymore.
Not since Braniff moved out.
- You know, he sure doesn'’t
take directions very well.
He wasn'’t supposed
to land in L.A. at all.
I think he deserves
whatever he'’s getting.
- He'’s pulling into
a Texaco station.
- You can trust your plane
to the guys who are inane.
- Hello? Fill '’er up?
Hello?
Somebody check the oil?
- Wow that was some sneeze
back there. Ugh.
- Good thing he packed a hanky.
- Joel, I think we'’re in for a
long, hard ride with this film.
- Yeah.
Mr. Goodwrench?
- Hello? Anybody here?
- Goober? Chico? Man?
- Don'’t get discouraged.
Come on, you guys. Wake up.
- Huh. [Snores]
- Mom? Mom, it'’s me.
They won'’t fill up my tank, Mom.
- Now listen, son.
You can'’t call me
every time you get a little
ripple in your fantasy world.
You have to live your own life.
You'’re 45 years old.
When are you going to realize
and when are you going to learn
you got to live on your own and
start taking care of yourself?
Got to realize this.
And I won'’t carry on anymore.
- Sorry, Mom.
- Maybe I dialed wrong.
Let me try again.
Let'’s see. Zero.
- Hi, this is the human race.
We'’re not in right now.
Please speak clearly
after the sound of the bomb.
- Well, looks like it'’s just
you and me, little darling.
Kind of like it that way
actually.
- There'’s no stronger bond than
that between man and plane.
- Come in, L.A. Come in.
[Horn honks]
- Huh?
- That'’s okay. I'’ve got a ride.
- Hello.
Where did you drop from?
I'’m Professor Galbraith.
These are my daughters
Lisa and Bonnie.
- Tom Gregory. Bonnie. Lisa.
Were you able to contact anyone
on your plane radio?
Hey, it'’s not such
a plain radio.
- ...they died out.
What'’s going on here?
- Oh, get in Mr. Gregory.
- Wait a minute.
I'’ve got to check my plane in.
- Mr. Gregory, I'’m sure you
realize there'’s nobody here.
- Mr. Gregory,
will you please get in?
- At least take me to a phone.
That one over there
is out of order.
[Imitates porn music]
- Bye.
- Will somebody please tell me
what'’s happened?
- Well, you signed a contract
that your agent couldn'’t get you
out of and, uh...
- Would you like to tell me?
- Well, first the slime people
came.
And then the whole army came
to fight them. And they lost.
Then the slime men
built a big wall.
But before it got hardened,
Los Angeles was evacuated.
And everybody'’s gone
but the slime men.
- She is hopped up
on sugar or something.
- Well, why are you here?
- We were up in the hills
at the cabin.
By the time we heard about
evacuating,
the wall had closed up.
So we'’re stuck.
But Dad'’ll get us out.
He'’s a science professor.
- And a crack pastry chef.
- That'’s about the way
it happened.
And you actually came through
that, huh?
- Well, I came through
something rough.
But it wasn'’t a solid wall.
- Well, no,
it'’s more like a dome.
And it covers the top part of
the city as well.
Now we'’ve always known that
there were fish in the ocean,
haven'’t we?
- Oh, that'’s a little
far fetched.
- Would you kindly let me out
right here?
- Now wait a minute.
This is no joke.
There are quite a few million
people who wish it were.
Look over there.
- Oh, God!
It'’s the Watts district.
- ...is an invasion
from a race of people
who have lived
right underneath our feet.
- Professor,
I know something has happened.
But have you ever seen
these slime people?
- No, but I'’ve had lengthy
phone conversations
with their head office.
- Look over there.
[Doors open]
- Hey, can we borrow your car?
- Look at them. Look at them!
- S'’all right?
- All right.
She'’s dead too.
- Good.
- Wow. And the dipstick
on this thing is enormous.
- Well, you'’re a pretty big
dipstick yourself, old man.
Let'’s get out of here, you guys.
- I'’m keeping it.
- All rise, hear ye, hear ye.
The honorable Judge Joel
presiding.
- Please be seated.
Bots v. Commando Cody.
Docket 212349-7A.
- Your honor,
the bots will prove
that the defendant,
Commando Cody,
is guilty of the following
felony charges.
Failure to follow
a proper flight plan.
Reckless endangerment
of the public.
Breaking the laws of physics
and gravity.
And acting as an officer of
the law and simply bad acting.
- Commando Cody,
how do you plead?
- We plead hardship, your honor.
My client, Commando Cody,
has more than paid
his debt to society
by being trapped
in pathetic serial.
Not to mention he'’s kept
the world safe
from Krog and his death ray.
- I object.
- Overruled.
Present your case, Mr. Crow.
- Mr. Cody, in episode one
you tweaked your nipples
and launched yourself into
the air without first contacting
the nearest FAA control tower,
didn'’t you?
- Objection. The use of the term
"nipples" is imprecise,
incorrect, and misleading.
Though I'’ll admit,
mildly provocative.
- Sustained.
- Mr. Cody,
your flying stunts may look
realistic on the silver screen,
but in fact they are nothing
more than simple
blue screen tricks.
Nothing more than Hollywood
hocus pocus, whoo-ha.
- Objection, your honor.
Mr. Mason is yet again
engaging in another of a series
of courtroom gymnastics.
- Your honor,
I'’m simply trying to prove
that Mr. Cody is nothing more
than a fictional character
in a lame series.
Or a lame character
in a fictional series.
- Your honor, I shall prove
beyond a shadow of a doubt
that Commando Cody
is in fact real.
I have here millions of letters
delivered by the U.S. Postal
Service who are never,
or at least seldom, wrong.
Letters from children of America
who believe in Cody
and what he stands for.
- I--I object, your honor.
My case on Cody is based on
hearsay and rumor.
- Really? I thought it was
shoddy planning and forethought.
- Well, they helped.
- Mr. Servo,
where are these letters
of which you speak?
- Hit is Cambot.
- Oh! I don'’t believe this.
- Out of order?
You'’re out of order!
He'’s out of order!
We'’re all out of order!
This courtroom is out of order!
This country is out of order!
- We'’ve got commercial sign.
Let'’s go.
- Out of order!
- I'’m ready to believe you.
But slime men who build
a dome...
- Here we go again.
- Okay. But you'’ve never
seen them, right?
- No.
- Well, maybe we can.
I'’m a newscaster. Sports mostly.
- So I work with slime
all the time.
- ...bound to be film on this.
- Oh, good.
- That Tom Gregory.
- How about it, Professor?
- I think it'’s a splendid idea.
- We can turn it in to
a road trip.
- We may be able to get some
additional data
that would be invaluable to us.
- And could you stop
at a Walmart? I need some Tums.
- I'’ll be darn.
Sorry, Professor, guess
I didn'’t want to believe you.
Here we are. Slime people.
- 1964. Robert Hutton, director.
A Golan Globus production.
- Why don'’t you put it on
and skip to the end,
and we can all get out of here?
- Dad, why does all of this
have to happen to us?
- Why did a goofy old
apocalypse have to happen
right when my acne
was clearing up?
- Now let'’s watch this film
and see if we can learn anything
about their mysterious wall.
- Oh, good.
Maybe it'’ll be a Chilly Willy
or a Droopy cartoon.
- Here'’s a late bulletin,
ladies and gentlemen.
- It'’s Droopie.
- ...have been found murdered
on and near the beaches tonight.
All beach communities
are being alerted.
If you are in the beach area,
do not leave your home.
As a special service,
I'’m informed now
that we are setting up
a remote unit on the spot.
And we'’ll bring you firsthand
news of this tragedy.
Stay tuned for future bulletins.
- But first a beauty makeover.
- We'’re at the scene
of still another murder...
- How'’d he get there?
He was just in the other place.
- ...a young engineer was found
not 20 minutes ago in this spot.
Is Ms. Castillo here?
- An old Orson Welles gag.
- You witnessed this,
didn'’t you?
- Yes, from my window. I saw it.
- They'’re talking
to a Pez dispenser.
- That man,
he got out of his car.
And they came at him
from the sewers
- Well here, have Pez.
- The things! They killed him.
And he screamed!
- Make you feel better.
- Ms. Castillo. Ms. Castillo.
That was Ms. Castillo,
eyewitness to the latest murder.
We'’ll stay by our unit to hear
at our mobile unit
for further reports.
You stay tuned to KTTV.
Vince Williams signing off
for now.
The report of large,
monstrous creatures--
- It'’s the All Vince network.
- All Vince, all the time.
- The military forces today
evacuated all the beach areas.
They are now engaged in
hand-to-hand combat...
- It'’s a hand-to-fin combat.
It'’s believed that they are
all within this area now,
north of Santa Monica.
- Right there.
- However,
residents of all areas
are warned to stay indoors
and barricade their homes.
Do not attempt,
according to authorities,
to evacuate at this time.
Stay in your homes.
- If it'’s yellow, let it mellow.
- Should be over
by this morning.
Stay indoors tonight.
We'’ve canceled all broadcasts
to bring you information
about the fighting.
- We'’re trying
to keep a lid on this thing.
- We'’ve asked Dr. Timothy Breaux
to our studio tonight.
He has seen the creatures
and has been in consultation
with the army.
- What it is, Dr. Breaux!
- We have late reports
from several sources
about these creatures.
But you saw them.
Are they from outer space?
Are they animals? What are they?
I believe they are
a form of animal life
but not from outer space.
- Then where are they from?
- The ones I saw came from
underground out of the sewers.
- The sewers?
- Yes.
- But of course I'’m flying
right now too.
- ...by the authorities that
these creatures have existed
in the subterranean areas.
- But why have they attacked us?
- It'’s mostly my fault,
actually.
And my I say how sorry I am.
- ...and nuclear devices.
I believe that this has
seriously disturbed
their former homes.
They have been forced by us
to seek shelter above ground.
That is why we have fog.
- But how do they make fog?
- I really don'’t know.
But one thing is certain.
The ring of fog that they have
thrown around and above the city
is an attempt to permanently
lower our temperature
so that they can live forever
above ground.
- Dr. Breaux, exactly what
do these creatures look like?
- They'’re large, huge...
- Big almost.
- ...prehistoric, covered with
scales and covered with slime.
- The slime people.
- Well, I wouldn'’t say that.
- Excuse me, doctor.
- Zsa Zsa is guilty.
- I have a late bulletin here.
We have a report that
a reinforcements have arrived
to join the forces
now fighting the slime people.
More units are on their way
across the country.
Residents are warned
not to leave their homes.
Repeat stay indoors
until further notice.
- Play board games or something.
The one with the pictures
is kind of fun.
- ...200 feet from here.
This area has been searched
and reported clear
of slime people.
Although the battle still rages
north of the city.
Casualties have been tremendous
in these two days of fighting.
- Ah,
that'’s impressive casualties.
- ...all points
of the normal fog.
Here in the quiet area,
men are working
trying to clear
the area of the fog.
It is believed that if we do
clear the fog,
the battle will be over.
Meantime, planes are overhead
seeding the clouds
and hoping that rain
will clear the air.
I hope I'’m still visible
in here.
- Huh?
- It can'’t be! It'’s hardened.
The fog has hardened.
- Somebody get in here quick!
- Unharden that man!
What are you trying to do,
make me look bad?
- It'’s horrible.
It'’s thickening.
- You saw it. There'’s a man
in the fog. It'’s hardened.
It'’s a solid wall in there.
Colonel, Colonel can you tell me
what'’s happening, sir?
- Uh, yes, the fog has hardened.
- The fog seems to have turned
to stone all around the city.
- What about the army?
- They'’ve hardened too.
- They'’re on the other side
of the wall now.
- They'’ve been forced out
completely.
Looks as if the slime people
have won for now.
Are you on television?
- Yes, sir. We are. Right there.
- Well, here are official orders
for complete evacuation
immediately.
All civilian and military
personnel must leave the area.
I repeat. All civilian
and military personnel
must leave the area.
- Elvis has left the building.
- ...and we'’ve set up emergency
shelters on the other side.
Of course, we will try
to continue penetrating
the fog wall
after everybody is out.
- Thank you, Colonel. That'’s it.
Everybody evacuate to the south
or east. Evacuate immediately.
- Well, that'’s the way
it all began.
- You have any more?
- Yeah, there'’s one more.
- Aah!
- It'’s Roger Ebert!
- Look, Gene, I thought
it was shoddy and manipulative.
A shameless tearjerker.
I give it a thumbs down.
- I liked it, Roger. I thought
that dancing was uplifting.
- Who are they?
- Critics.
- Looters. After our money or--
- Tom,
they'’re not our problem now.
It'’s getting close
to the dew point.
- You mean,
they'’ll be coming out soon?
- Let'’s get to Studio One.
It'’s got double doors.
- Double doors. Great big
French windows, a sauna.
You'’ll love it.
Everybody step this way.
- So do we assume now
that Vince is dead?
- Over there!
- Oh.
- Ah, guys, it'’s just me.
You'’re old friend Joe.
I have a staph infection
and eczema.
But hey, come on guys.
Let me come with you.
I'’m not gonna kiss you,
you know.
- Hurry!
- Aah!
- Fabian.
- Am I glad to see you.
They'’re coming
by the hundreds out there.
- Tom, we don'’t have much time.
They must'’ve seen me.
Come on, down here.
- Well, it'’s a broken water main
all right, Ralphie boy.
- Like the film?
- Okay everybody, stop.
Look scared. Move on.
Thank you. Everybody.
Stop, good.
- Come on, Marie, push.
There we go.
Come on. Everybody in here now.
- Now close it up.
- It'’s moving!
- Stop that! It tickles. Heh.
- Help me with this door.
- Great. Now they'’re
in slackhouse funf.
- Tom, do you think
that'’ll hold '’em?
- Don'’t worry, honey.
Just hope we keep getting power.
- Incidentally,
my name'’s Calvin Johnson.
- So what?
- Just call me Cal.
- Hey, Cal.
My daughters Lisa and Bonnie.
- And this is Tom Gregory.
- How are you?
- Odds are getting mighty unfair
out there.
Sure glad I ran into you.
- Guess we'’re all lucky
to be in here.
- There'’s a lot of actors
who aren'’t even working.
- Come on.
- It'’s not much.
But I call it hell.
- What are you doing?
- We left some looters behind
in the projection room.
They'’re no friends of mine.
But at least we can warn them.
- Hello no friends of mine.
- Listen to me. If you'’re
still in there, look out.
Barricade the doors.
Get the seats up against them.
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Oh, it'’s Tom Waits
on a bender.
- Must be the new
Hi-C ecto cooler.
- Oh, that water main is going
to cost you 500 bucks.
- Hey, it'’s Michael J. Pollard.
- Which one?
- That guy.
- Who are you?
- Bobcat Goldthwait.
- Ow! Aah!
- So much for Police Academy 8.
- Tickle machine.
Tickle machine.
- Professor, would you mind
sitting over there
next to Bonnie?
I'’m going to try
to get a message out.
- Keep your hands to yourself.
- I doubt very much
whether anything will get
through that dome.
- But there'’s no harm trying.
Cal, swing that monitor
around this way, will you?
Now if our picture is getting
through,
we'’ll see it right there.
- Are we going to be
on television?
- Yes. But our Nielsen rating
won'’t be very high.
- If you'’ll hold that card
right up to camera, okay.
Cal, you can sit there on the
arm right next to the professor.
- But keep your hands
to yourself.
- Now just relax,
and I'’ll switch on the camera.
- Now has everyone swallowed
their barium?
- Let'’s all keep our fingers
crossed, huh?
- Professor,
sing the theme song and...yes.
This is Slime Witness News
with anchorperson Ernie Cofax.
- This is KTTV Studios
in Hollywood.
If you are receiving
this signal,
please contact authorities
and us if at all possible.
- There'’s nothing
on the monitor.
Does that mean they
can'’t hear us?
- We left the lens cap on.
- Oh!
- You know,
there'’s a slight chance
they might pick up the audio.
I'’ll give it a whirl anyway.
This is KTTV Studios in
Hollywood to Mt. Wilson.
We are being attacked
by the slime people.
- Send reams of Kleenex.
- If you have any information
about this wall,
please contact us immediately.
- Or Pink Floyd.
- If anybody'’s listening,
this is no joke.
I'’m a Marine.
- I'’d like to sing a melody
to the King'’s greatest hits.
- I guess they thought
I was dead and left me there.
The slime people made a fog.
And the fog...
- Boy,
I hate these pledge drives.
- ...knows how
to get through this thing,
then I'’m sure that there'’s a few
other people just like us...
- I spent a year working with
these special individuals
and seen more love come
out of their tiny hearts.
- Do you think anybody heard it?
- Aah!
- Huh?
- What'’s wrong?
We'’re losing power fast.
- Where'’s he going, Dad?
- I think he'’s trying
to conserve electricity.
- Hmm.
- There we go. I just
rewired the entire studio.
- That'’ll last us through
the night, I hope.
- It'’s dead. Nothing.
- I was hoping we could find out
what was going on outside
the dome.
- Maybe Cal can help us.
Cal, did you actually
see the wall?
- No, I saw them on the dark
side of the moon tour.
- One minute there was just
a fog,
the next got thick and hard.
- Did you touch it?
Was it hot or cold?
Or rough or smooth? Or what?
- I didn'’t get close enough.
The slime men were coming back.
And all I saw was...
- Oh, heck,
I disgraced myself like crazy.
- ...coming in all around.
I didn'’t see anything else.
That'’s when I came back here.
I hid all last night.
Spent a day trying to find out
if there was anybody else
besides me
that was alive in here.
- Was there besides us?
- I ran across some looters
and a couple of people going
crazy trying to get out.
And some that was so scared
they wouldn'’t even talk to me.
- Anyone else?
- Not alive.
- Well, I suggest that we try
to get some rest.
Tomorrow, Cal can take us
to where he first saw the wall.
- Berlin?
- We can hold up every chemical
we possibly can
to try and see
what penetrates it.
- There ought to be one.
- Ought to be?
Professor, there'’s got to be.
- Should be.
- I'’ll take first watch.
- There you are, Cal.
- That'’s not a watch.
That'’s a gun.
- This is how I keep time,
city boy.
- Cal? Cal?
- Do you have a hall pass,
Bonnie?
I'’ll have to shoot you
if you don'’t.
Why aren'’t you sleeping
like the others?
- I couldn'’t sleep.
Knowing those things are
out there gives me the creeps.
- I know. But I'’ll warn you
in plenty of time
if anything happens.
Now you go on back
with the others.
We'’re going to have
a big day tomorrow.
I'’d rather stay with you.
Don'’t you want me to?
- Sure. But--
- Well, then it'’s all settled.
- There is something
I wanted to ask you.
Did you have a boyfriend
before all this happened?
- Only barrack 14.
- I had lots of dates.
But there was no one special.
You know, just Elvis and,
oh, Jerry Lee.
- Do you care?
- Not at all.
That'’s why I'’m talking to you.
- I was just wondering.
Your dad was acting
kind of funny.
Did he care that I came along?
- He'’s just worried about
getting us out of here.
I'’m sure he didn'’t mind.
Wouldn'’t have left anybody
out there.
- Am I just anybody?
- I don'’t think so.
- You'’re nobody.
- You'’re so brave.
I mean, fighting and everything.
- I didn'’t do any more than
what my buddies would'’ve done.
I don'’t think so.
- Bonnie,
do you use heavy makeup
to cover up your mustache?
- Bonnie...
- Can you field strip an M-16?
- Mmm. You taste like root beer
barrels.
- Maybe I shouldn'’t
have done that.
- Give me back my gum!
- I don'’t know.
I think I kind of liked it.
- Hey, Mikey, she likes it.
- I'’m not the kind of guy
that just goes around
kissing any girl.
- Well,
just any girl that says yes.
- I'’m glad.
Because when we get out of here,
I want to see a lot more of you.
Right now I'’ve got a job to do.
- I know.
- Gee whiz.
You know as long as
you'’re sittin'’ here,
I don'’t even want
to think about slime people.
Although it'’s hard looking
at a mug like yours.
You'’d better get out of here.
right now, you hear?
- A Marine that says "gee whiz."
What'’s he going to do?
Storm the Cunningham house?
- Bonnie...
goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- Young love.
- Hey come everybody, get up.
You'’re making union scale.
What do you want? Wake up.
- Uh, excuse me, Mr. Mailman.
Uh, Mr. Letterman'’s looking
for you.
There'’s no sign of them
anywhere outside.
- Oh, is it cooler
than yesterday?
- I think it is.
Does that mean--
- Oh, no.
- Yep.
- I hate when they do that.
- They'’re trying to bring
our temperature down
to a constant dew point.
That way they'’ll be able
to circulate on the surface
both day and night.
- I, uh--I checked
your station wagon.
It hasn'’t been touched.
- My car'’s there too.
- Good.
- Hear them run.
- All right, come on, my
sleeping beauties.
Up and at '’em.
- Here we go.
- Good morning, Tom.
- Morning.
- What do you suggest we do now,
sir?
- Let'’s twist.
- ...we'’ve got to break
that wall and get through
in a matter of a few hours.
- Then we can shower up
and make the party, Dad.
- ...list of things here
that we'’ll need.
This plus the chemicals
that I'’ll get from the
laboratory will give us a start.
- An awful lot, Dad.
- It'’s an awful lot, Dad.
- We'’ve got mine too.
It'’s in the garage.
- I suggest that we divide up.
That'’ll give us a chance to get
this shopping done much quicker.
- Good idea or looting.
- Cal, you take
my station wagon.
- He'’d rather have the girl.
Find the nearest surplus store
and get these items.
- Yes, sir.
- He'’s going to need help
with all that, Dad.
I'’ll go with him.
- All right, Bonnie.
Take good care of her, Cal.
- I will, sir. I promise.
- That'’s what he'’s afraid of.
- Come on, honey. Here we go.
Professor.
- ♪ 99 bottles of beer
on the wall ♪
- And remember, folks,
even at the end of the world,
signal those turns.
- Such dramatic driving music.
- Hey, nice cups.
- You see, Tom, this wall that
they'’ve thrown around the city
is evidently some sort of
dome-like affair.
Otherwise, we would have
the military planes
bombing us from above.
- Have you any idea
how they make it?
- It'’s probably
subcontracted out.
- With some sort of machine
or mechanism.
They probably inject
some element
into a controlled air mass.
- Like heroine.
- This combines chemically
with an element
in our atmosphere.
Probably nitrogen.
Thereby forming
a solid compound.
Oh, Lisa, you ought to pack
enough food supplies
for a couple of days.
- Sure, Mr. Hefner.
- Poor little Bonnie must just
be famished.
- Yeah,
I'’ll get busy in the lab.
- And we'’ll get busy
in the kitchen. Heh heh.
- How about me making us
some coffee?
- Where is it?
- Right here.
- Man, I don'’t know about you,
Professor,
but I got a thing about women
on stepladders.
- ...you'’re quite a gal.
- As someone who'’s trying to get
us out of all this,
I think you should have more
important things on your mind.
- Love coffee.
- Awful lot.
- Oh, tasting my daughter,
I see.
Well, I'’ll just stare
at these curtains.
- Penetrating that wall
may prove to be
a very valuable experiment.
If anything like this ever
happens again.
- We got to go, you guys.
- It was just getting
interesting.
- Tell me about it.
- You know what it'’s like being
the daughter of a scientist.
- It'’s not dull.
Here, let me help you.
- Joel, I don'’t understand
why this movie was made.
- What'’s that, Crow? Why?
- I just don'’t understand why
someone would spend so much time
trying to make a movie
that was obviously
conjured up over lunch.
- Yeah, it is sort of
a loose end festival.
Like,
what are these slime people?
They can'’t really be reptiles,
Because reptiles need heat
to live.
And they'’re trying to make it
cold on the planet.
- Yeah. And how did they
become slime people
living in the center
of the earth and all.
As far as I know,
slime isn'’t exactly a naturally
occurring element
even in the bowels of the earth.
- Yeah, I think it would'’ve been
much more believable
if they would'’ve made them
monsters invading from space.
You know, then at least
they could play by rules
we can'’t even comprehend.
- Well, the thing is, you guys,
the real beauty part
of this movie is that
it actually got made.
You know, the guy who made it
isn'’t a fool.
He just convinced some people
that it was worth making.
You know, whether it was a good
idea or it could make money
or it satisfied some bizarre
urge in the viewing public.
- Oh, I see. So it'’s
the gullibility of humans
that allows things like this
to exist.
- I guess you'’re right. Yeah.
- So I could make a movie about
a giant apple sauce monster
who goes around smooshing up
people'’s food
until there'’s nothing left
to chew on the planet.
- Provided you could get
someone to pay for it,
think it was a good idea
and worth making.
- Oh, well, I have a good idea
for a show then.
I'’m sure it'’ll work.
Okay. This guy gets stranded
on a desert isle.
He makes little mechanical
friends from parts of his boat.
Then all day long they have
to sit and watch reruns
of bad TV shows,
like Super Train
or Greatest American Hero.
- Oh, no, what would they eat?
- It doesn'’t matter.
You should just relax.
It'’s just a show.
- Well, why would they be
watching the shows then?
- Uh, how about
if two evil commodores
send the shows to him?
- Yeah!
- Uh, I don'’t think so.
It'’s very illogical.
Wouldn'’t fly.
- Really?
- Nope.
- Too far fetched.
- Yep.
- Well, let'’s got think
of some more, Servo.
Maybe we could get rich.
- Yeah.
- You know, you give life
to two inanimate objects
and they turn around
and mock your entire species.
You know, if I'’m ever trapped
in outer space again,
I think I'’m just going to--
[Alarm sounds]
- Oh, we got movie time!
Oh-ho
- We did our best, sir.
We ran into a gang of people
looting store.
They were getting too close
so we had to leave.
- What now, sir?
- To the wall.
We surveyed it from our house.
- Tom! Tom Gregory, old chap.
- Tom? Who'’s that?
- The goat man.
- Toliver. He'’s a great writer.
But the biggest troublemaker
I'’ve ever known.
Besides, I think
he'’s a potential psycho.
- Hi, I'’m goat man.
- Kitty.
- Say, are you driving
this old, worn out heap?
It goes, Toliver.
- Well, I suppose
it'’ll have to do.
Would you mind assisting me
with the only faithful
old friend I have left
in this world?
- Sure, where is he?
- Toliver, have you heard
of the slime people?
- No, but if you hum a few bars,
I could pick it up.
It'’s all a lot of nonsense.
I'’ve been right over there
in my cabin all the time.
And I haven'’t seen a one of '’em.
Although I would like to,
if they exist.
I'’ve decided to do a book
exposing all the insanity
that'’s going on around here.
- I call it the dictionary.
- That might work better if you
just made it into a coat
rather than just carrying
it around all the time.
- ...to run. These fools!
- Don'’t point that goat at me.
It might go off.
- Evacuation.
- Sounds painful.
If there are any beings,
they'’re probably
as harmless as ants.
- Obviously, he didn'’t see
the movie Them.
- Don'’t leave him, Tom.
- Oh, all right,
you lovable old coot.
You little subplot, come on.
- I'’ll show you all the slime
people you want to see, get in.
- I'’ll go along with you.
If you'’re going downtown,
I can gather some material.
By the way,
please give me my little love.
- No, no.
I'’m afraid he'’s not on the list.
- Run along, Pan.
- We'’re not brining
your magazines either.
- [Sniffs] Whoo!
You work around circus animals?
Whoo.
- When cars ruled the earth.
- Looks like it'’s a radiator
problem to me.
- Well, here we are
at the Shriners'’ picnic.
- That fog is thicker than
Grandma'’s mustache.
- Oh, Tom, there it is.
Somewhere in there is the wall.
- All right, Cal,
you stay here with the girls.
Tom, you bring the ropes
and the weapons,
and we'’ll go have a look at what
our friends have built for us.
- Goat man will be bait.
- ...the wall.
Well, there'’s six degrees to go.
Bonnie, you watch your meter.
When it reaches dew point,
have Cal fire a shot.
Now we'’ll give two tugs on the
rope if we run into any trouble.
- Better take this.
- Thanks.
- The money?
- ...they'’ll be in there?
- We'’re only going
about 300 feet.
Just enough to find the wall.
All right? Let'’s go.
- If you drag out our rotting,
broken carcasses,
it means it didn'’t really work
out very well.
- Breathe all right?
- Oh, excuse me.
- Well, it'’s very interesting.
- Atmosphere seems normal.
No lack of oxygen.
No trace of poison gas.
Keep an eye out
for any movement though.
- Maybe there is no wall.
Maybe it'’s sort of
a high pressure dip area.
- It'’s only two degrees above
where Dad made the line, Cal.
- Wow, you'’re easily pleased.
- Hey, Joel, are they
in the Smoky Mountains?
- No.
- On top of old smoky?
- Smack him, Joel.
- No, I wouldn'’t do that.
- Yeah, you would.
- Professor.
Come here.
I thought I saw something
move down there.
- It'’s nothing. Just my heart
beating for you, Tom.
- I can'’t see anything.
Let'’s move on.
- It'’s the thing from
The Fantastic Four.
- No, that'’s Arty Johnson.
- Oh.
- I love the smell of napalm
in the morning.
Smells like...slime.
- Lovely. Lovely.
- It jerked a few times.
- Well, lead him on.
- Now it'’s pulling away.
- Keep your rod tip high.
- I'’m gonna go and see
what happened.
- Set the hook!
- Dad told you to stay here!
- Tom is probably in there
falling over his own feet,
lying inundated
in his own blood.
- Shut up.
- Wait a minute, Lisa!
- Lisa! Bonnie!
Take this, Toliver.
- Hey, thanks for the twine,
cutey pie.
- Magic rope.
Oh, what a time to lose
your contact.
Now everybody'’s going
to have to look for it.
- Here, Tom, this is their wall.
- What? Are we walking through
a music video?
- Now, Tom, will you open up
those chemicals, please?
- This is Curt Gaudi.
This week
on the American Sportsman
we'’re hunting for slime people
with Forest Kelly.
- Silicon. Great for caulking
around windows
and some cosmetic uses as well.
- Try the potassium.
It'’s marked with K.
- There you are.
- And it'’s tasty.
- Sure, let the girl go first.
Real nice, you guys.
- Careful, Tom,
something'’s coming.
That'’s your department.
- You'’re in charge
of human resources.
- It'’s like
a mime training course.
- Tom, are you all right?
- What the devil
are you doing here?
- What happened?
- Bonnie, what'’s wrong?
- I thought you signaled
you were in trouble, sir.
- Well,
we might as well start back.
Nothing else we have to use.
There are thousands of chemicals
that we haven'’t used, of course.
Must be something that'’ll
penetrate that wall. But what?
- Maybe a hair pin?
- Right there, dear.
- Aah! Dad! Dad!
- Let'’s get out of here.
- Good idea.
- You know, I can'’t tell,
but I bet it'’s really action
packed under all this fog.
- Hey,
he'’s doing interpretive dance.
- Looks like a kindergarten
field trip.
- Yeah, to Scab World.
- Real scary being chased
by a giant crawdad.
You'’re on your own,
Cayenne Pepper. Whoo-whee.
Slime people.
- That thing they'’re hanging
onto must be the plot line.
- Those guys are slime.
- All right, everybody in.
Field trip'’s over.
Turn the defroster on.
- What'’s everyone want?
Burgers? Chicken?
[Tires screech]
- Has he got a license?
Hey, kid, what do you think
you'’re doing, flying a jet?
- Do you realize
the situation, sir?
- Look, Professor,
I'’ve been through a war.
I'’ve seen people panic
and run 100 times.
Maybe 10 times
they had a reason.
The other 90,
they were just stupid.
Crazed with idiotic fear.
Whichever is the case here,
it would still make
a darn good book.
- Shut up.
- I'’d put you in it too,
Professor.
Hey, kid,
drop me off anywhere here.
I'’ve got a hike to jack
the beach combers.
I feel an inspiration
to start right in.
I'’ll--I'’ll open with you
characters in the fog.
- Drop Mr. Toliver off.
- And don'’t slow down.
- This looks fine right here.
Maybe they got a typewriter
in this joint.
- So long characters.
- Keep the meter running.
- Why are we stopping here?
- Believe it or not,
it'’s what he wants.
- Toliver!
Come on, nobody'’s home!
- Genius waits for no one.
- But stupidity hammers
on deserted buildings.
- I'’ll break a window.
- Huh? What?
- Boy, I'’d bet that'’d be scary
if we could make out
what it was.
- Aah! Aah!
- Let'’s get out of here, Scooby.
[Car engine starts]
- I'’ve never seen anything
like it.
- Even in Tijuana.
- They'’re not human.
They'’re monsters.
- People. Lots of '’em.
- Wish we had one of them
station wagons.
- Look, they'’re all on their way
to a George Romero
film festival.
- Get back! Get in!
- What the--oh, my gosh.
We'’re out of gas.
- Oh, sure. That old trick.
He wants to make out
with the whole family.
- We'’ll make a run for it.
- It'’s a butcher shop.
How fitting.
- Oh, my goodness.
Tip roast is 79 cents.
- Of course it'’s high.
It is the apocalypse, you know.
Or the porkalypse.
Chicken lips.
- Anyway, it'’s a good thing
they'’re in a butcher shop.
In case somebody
gets a black eye,
they'’ll have a steak there
they can put it on.
- Yeah.
- Seems safe enough.
- I'’ll see where this one goes,
just in case.
- Aah! Look!
- Oh, man.
You got glass in the kielbasa.
- Come here.
- Hey, what kind of price you
got on ground chuck today?
- They'’re after real low prices.
Has-been actor, 79 cents.
Juicy 18 year olds,
3.95 a pound.
- Just like the hero does.
- He'’s just a story.
Die, you monster!
You'’re not real!
Go on.
- Well, at least now they'’ll
be plenty of ham steak.
- Looks like Toliver
is this week'’s special.
- Tom, don'’t leave him out
there. You'’ve got to help him.
- Stop it, Lisa! Stop it!
- Lisa.
- Shut up.
- There'’s nothing we can do now.
- Oh, we should be safe in here.
It'’s a meat locker.
Metal door back, front.
It should hold '’em.
- What difference does it make?
We'’re stuck in this refrigerator
with those things out there.
- That'’s enough, Bonnie.
Now let'’s get one thing
straight.
Toliver is dead.
- So?
- He had the same chance
for safety that we all had.
Is that understood?
Fear killed Toliver.
- No, I thought it was those
big guys in the costumes.
- I'’m sorry, Tom.
- Me too.
- All right. Now if we expect
to get out of here in one piece,
it'’s going to take all the nerve
we'’ve got and then some.
- You'’d better order out
for more nerve.
- I don'’t expect you to act
as if nothing'’s happened.
But you'’ve got to keep calm.
- Come on, Bonnie.
- Remember, keep cool.
- Oh, Fabian gets off
a good one.
- They'’re wonderful.
Both of them.
Tom, you'’d better come with me.
We'’ve got to make some plans.
- He asked me. He asked me.
- Uh, Cal, there'’s a bug
on your hand there.
Got it.
- Ew, what is that?
What is that stuff?
- It'’s the rest of the movie.
- ...marinating meat.
- Tom, did you notice
any flashing
or a possible electrical field
or any heat
when you were in the plane?
- No. Unless you mean my own
temperature when I almost took
a fast dip into the ocean.
- Ah, he kills me, that guy.
- Of course,
there is a bright side to this.
The first chemicals you pick off
the shelves just might do it.
- Professor,
I don'’t see any slime men,
- Of course I'’ve got my eyes
squeezed tightly shut.
- Tom, what did you say
about your landing?
- The plane dove to the water.
It almost touched it.
- We could break their wall
with sodium chloride.
- Oh, you mean
ordinary table salt?
Ah!
- What'’s sodium chloride?
- Sodium chloride is table salt.
Salt has to be the answer.
'’Cause the dome cannot
become solid
for a good number of feet
above the ocean.
The spray from the saltwater
won'’t permit it.
And that'’s how Tom got through.
- And why aren'’t the Navy subs
coming in?
- They probably haven'’t stumbled
onto it yet.
- Is there enough salt here,
Dad?
- I hope.
- You know, that plane
was pretty well watered down.
Why don'’t we find everything
we can to make a vehicle?
- But that'’ll take hours.
And we still have to find
the car.
We can'’t just walk through
slime men looking for more salt.
- Hey, come on. It'’s not the end
of the world, you Gloomy Guses.
- But it is.
- Doh!
- What are they building?
A float?
- Something with salt
and really get out of here.
- I hope she asks me
to the Sadie Hawkins dance.
- I'’ll find a car
and bring it back.
- I'’ll go with you.
- No, you stay here.
And don'’t tell them I'’ve gone.
They'’d just come looking.
- Why should I just sit here
and not do anything either?
- '’Cause you'’re a pawn
in a much larger game.
- Cal, I can help you.
- In ways you never
knew possible.
- But you stay close to me
all the time.
- Okay.
- If he starts singing
"Oh, What a Beautiful Morning"
I'’m gonna lose it.
- We got to stay over this way.
Back there is the wall.
You stay far away from there.
- Kids, do not play on, in,
or around dumpsters.
- Behind you.
- Hey, white trash meets
real trash.
- Bonnie?
- Those crazy kids
walked right out.
- Well, they must be near.
It'’s only a minute
since they left. Unless...
- Oh, Tom, let'’s go
and find them, please.
- No, no. You stay here.
You work on the car.
Both of you.
Makes more sense that way.
Honey, hand me that gun.
- Stay up at the counter
in case we have some customers.
- You be careful, Tom.
- I will.
- Um...dumpster.
- Dumpster, ah.
- Look out!
- Dumpster. [Mumbling]
- Bonnie!
Bonnie!
- Dumpster!
- Watch out!
- Professor!
- How do slime monsters
get any traction?
- Hey, no deliveries
between 10:00 and 2:00.
Bonnie? Cal, where'’s Bonnie?
I don'’t know.
She was right there with me.
And then she was gone.
- I ran away
like a yellow belly.
- You didn'’t see any sign of--
Cal, she'’s not dead.
- She'’s probably having
the slime of her life.
- Oh, no. Not Bonnie.
- Well, parts of Bonnie.
- They'’ve taken her.
Probably to try and lure us
out in the open.
As long as they keep her alive,
they know we'’ll come out
after her.
- Where do you think
you'’re going?
- I'’m going after her.
I got her into this.
Now I'’ll get her out.
See this?
They used it on us.
I'’ll use it right back on them.
- Get back here.
- Would you like a copy
of our Watchtower?
- Lobster claws on sale.
2.19 a pound.
- Don'’t touch it, Tom.
- A good salesmen always
sticks his foot in the door.
- They'’re self-sealing.
- What? You mean?
A bullet makes a hole and then
closes up, is that right?
- That has got to hurt.
- Those are good
with drawn butter.
- When they fight among
themselves, the cap is removed,
the lance is hollow. Therefore
the hole doesn'’t close.
- Okay, now we know.
- He knows everything.
- ...I'’m gonna go after Bonnie.
- Well, you'’re not going to help
her by getting yourself killed.
Those creatures are right
outside that door.
They'’ll get you in a minute.
- Well, we just can'’t
let them have her!
- I'’ll bet they'’ve got
a headquarters nearby.
- Oh, my god.
Corned beef. 89 cents.
Joel, I can'’t believe this.
- Another victim of slime!
- Let'’s get him out of here.
- Nice guys. Thanks.
- How do you fight lightning
speed slime people like that?
- Better around that pole.
- Hubcap.
- They'’ll come back for it.
- He got the tire.
- You will believe
a Marine can drive.
- Daddy! Daddy!
- Shut up, I'’m your daddy now.
Daddy!
- The car'’s not moving.
- Don'’t stop the car.
Let '’em think we'’re still in it.
- Bad shocks.
- Oh, they saw Commando Cody.
- They gave the slime the slip.
- Cal, come here.
- Feel all right?
- I'’m all right.
- Now look,
we'’ve got to find their trail.
Footprints, slime, anything.
- Discarded Kleenex,
antihistamines, Neo-Synephrine.
Keep looking.
- What are we seeing?
- The future.
- Oh.
- Aah!
- Come on, baby.
We could have
a nice life together.
These scales aren'’t so bad
once you get used to them.
You'’ll callus up in a while.
- Aah!
Aah!
- Honestly, Bonnie,
the slime you bring home.
- A slime field outside of L.A.
and Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
are a thousand miles apart.
But they both mean one thing
to these guys.
And that'’s cold Milwaukee beer.
- Slime light.
- Slimeiken.
- Look at this. Blond hair.
- Yeah, you can usually find a
blond hair in a field of wheat.
- At night.
- In a fog.
- Come on. Let'’s go.
[Screaming]
- What was that?
[Screaming continues]
- I'’ll give you something
to scream about.
- He'’ll never make
Slime'’sMan of the Year.
- Oh, it'’s a good thing
they don'’t have eyes
on the back of their
exoskeletons.
- No professor'’s daughter
is worth that.
Let'’s make tracks, guys.
- Speaking of which,
we'’d better go pretty soon.
- Let'’s get out of here.
- We'’d better get out of here.
- Bye, guys.
Meet you back at the lodge.
[Screaming continues]
- What'’s with all this smoke?
Get up here, you guys.
Did you put a crack
in the bipolar defroculator
or something?
- Joel? What'’s the matter, Joel?
You scared?
- No, I'’m not scared.
I just wonder what
all this smoke'’s about. Come on.
- I'’d be scared if I were you,
Joel.
The slime people could be
somewhere in the fog.
- Yeah, Joel, nothing scarier
than a big, boiled lobster
with a bad, oozing head cold,
a big, scaly wart,
and crusted crab monster
leaking mucous--
- Okay.
Listen, okay, I get the point.
Now, come on. I'’m not scared.
But I just got to know
what'’s going on.
Well, the truth is, Joel,
we rigged Gypsy'’s thermal
conducer tube to create big,
billowy clouds
of terrifying slime smoke.
Pretty funny, huh?
- Yeah. Well, you guys have
to learn there'’s nothing scary
about a bunch of
out-of-work actors
parading around with
papier-mâché skin conditions.
- Yeah, they do kind of look
like Quasimodo with eczema,
don'’t they?
- Yeah, like a tree toad
with psoriasis.
- Exactly. Subterranean
alligators in body suits
come from underground
to make better lives
for themselves in L.A.
Unfortunately, the only way
they know how to communicate
is by impaling people
with prehistoric spears.
So they'’re not really so bad.
They'’re just misunderstood,
I think.
- Say, Joel, how come they have
a machine that can create
a solid rock-like wall
out of fog,
but they can'’t create,
oh say, a gun?
- Well, Crow, that'’s simple.
It'’s easy to understand.
'’Cause it'’s just a movie.
- Oh, yeah.
- All right, I got to go check
on Gypsy so this whole ship
doesn'’t fill with smoke.
- You know, Crow,
maybe next time
we should fill up the bridge
with deli style lemon whip
to scare '’em.
- Yeah! Or 7-layer salad.
- Yeah, that'’s a good idea.
- Or taco.
- With peas and stuff.
- We got commercial sign.
- Whoa.
- Are you all right?
- Sure, honey.
- They found Bonnie.
- Here you go.
- Believe me, it works.
- It'’s a good thing she'’s
the only human they didn'’t kill.
- Come on.
- Bonnie, I'’m sorry about
the whole dumpster slime thing.
- Look at that!
- I told you we should'’ve
of put the campfire out.
- The machine
that makes the wall.
- It'’s the Play-Doh Fun Factory.
- Tip O'’Neil 79 cents a pound.
- Francis Bacon,
three for a dollar.
- Lancelot Links, 2.49 a pound.
- Open up.
- Oh, Bonnie,
are you all right?
- Yeah, just a little slimy.
- Now, don'’t be afraid dear.
You'’re safe now.
Don'’t cry, dear.
You'’re all right.
- They kept dragging me around,
the sat me in the cave.
They were all around.
I couldn'’t get out!
- Don'’t, don'’t. We'’ll get
out of everything all right.
- I feel all oogy, Daddy.
- Lisa,
I think she'’d feel better
if you'’d help her clean up
a little bit.
- I think we'’d all feel better
if we cleaned her up a bit.
- If we'’d only evacuated
with the others.
None of this would'’ve happened.
- Well, I haven'’t figured out
anything really.
Except I marinated
a few t-bones.
- From now on I want you
to follow orders, okay.
- Wait, I'’m the Marine.
You'’re the sports reporter.
- That makes sense.
- I think we found
their machine.
- The machine that makes
the wall.
- What did it look like?
Were there any dials,
any levers,
anything we could reverse
to break the wall?
- The slime men were
coming back.
And we had to leave.
- Turned and ran again, huh?
- ...large, soft mass that came
out of some kind of a machine.
I'’ve never seen anything
like it before.
- That means we'’ll have to rely
on the salt.
- Let'’s try it.
- Wait a minute, Cal.
- How much salt do we have?
- Two buckets of solution.
- And a lot of those little,
tiny take-out packets.
- No, we haven'’t.
The slime people already have
our temperature under control.
- And they'’re not very gentle
when they use a thermometer.
- As long as we stay in here,
we'’re just setting ducks.
- No, sitting ducks.
- Where is this salt?
- Outside the door.
- I'’ll round them up.
- Come on, Lisa, Bonnie.
We'’re going through
that wall right now.
- Aren'’t men cool?
- Gals, bring those buckets.
- From now on
we call it sodium chloride.
It'’s sort of a code. They won'’t
know what we'’re talking about.
- Keep the buckets and your
purses separate everybody.
We don'’t won'’t to douse
the slime people with cosmetics.
- What happened to their car?
- Wrong way Marine guy decided
to let it drop off a cliff.
- That was a gripping scene.
- Well, here it is again
from a different angle.
- Why are those guys
still carrying guns?
They don'’t have any affect on
the slime people, we know that.
- It'’s so they don'’t have
to carry the buckets.
- Oh.
- Crafty.
- To a fault.
- Uh, what'’s
the professor carrying?
- Ah, the movie?
- A grudge maybe.
- The weight of the world.
- Oh a crime in etly, Joel.
What is this,
the Bataan death march?
- I think it'’s
the Bataan death watch.
- Quiet now.
- The headquarters
are right below us.
- Think they'’re using
a fog filter here?
- Girls, bring
the salt solution over here.
- Dad, what is all that noise.
- The military trying to break
through from the outside.
- Cal, did you bring
the rags and sticks?
- I got '’em.
- All right,
make some of those sticks.
Keep them well-soaked
in this solution
and apply them to this area
right here.
- Your thighs?
- Professor, come here.
- What is it, Tom?
- I'’m going down there
and get their machine.
- It'’s too much of a risk.
- Not right now.
The cave was clear
when we came up here.
They'’re probably still trying to
figure out where we took Bonnie.
- We'’ll try the salt first.
If that doesn'’t work--
- No, no,
there'’s not enough time.
- The ground pepper.
- The machine is down there.
- You know the odds of breaking
through that wall
with two buckets of solution?
- Dad, we'’ve almost used
half a pale.
You'’ve only made a small dent.
- Yeah,
but the odds have dropped.
- I'’m going after the machine.
- Tom, you can'’t.
- Honey, I have to.
- The end of the movie
depends on it.
- Cover me from the ridge.
- Cover you? I'’m going with you.
- No, you'’re not.
And that'’s an order.
You'’ll stay here and fire
if you run into any trouble.
- Wouldn'’t it be weird
if they just cleaned off
the camera lens
and all that fog went away?
- There are a lot of things
I want to tell you.
- And they all rhyme
with the letter k.
- All right.
- Kissing you is like plunging
my tongue
into a vat
of Shiitake mushrooms.
- Ick.
- Come on, Marine.
- Don'’t call me Marine. Geez.
- This looks like one long,
boring commercial
for London Fog raincoats.
- No sign of them yet. You know,
you'’d better let me go.
You may run into trouble.
- Oh, you really think I might?
Like these last two hours
didn'’t count as trouble?
- Now look, don'’t leave
no matter what happens.
Give me a chance to get
down there
and then signal you
if the coast is clear.
- You understand?
- Yes. But--
- No arguments.
- So let'’s see.
I tug on the rope twice.
- Oh, that was hours ago,
you idiot.
- Cal, do you think
he'’ll be all right?
- He can take care of himself.
- But he'’s all alone.
- We'’d better get back
to the wall, dear.
- I think one of us should'’ve
gone down there to help him.
- Aah!
- Get back!
I'’ll take care of them.
- Well, it looks like Mr. Slime
Monster really came to play.
Remember, folks, he'’s battling
with a bad head cold.
- Oh, look at that.
A blistering backhand.
- Luckily the Marine has
the fan support in this case.
- Up-ended him.
- I think it'’s going
to be close here.
Yes, it'’s a pole vault
to the face.
- And a mucous rollover.
- Ooh, a phlegm twist.
- Oh, look at this.
Cal is clearly unfamiliar
with the subterranean rules.
Proves my point, though.
Slime people have no traction.
- Cal, that noise will probably
bring more of them.
- They'’re down near
the bowels of the commercial.
- Yes, sir. It'’s not far.
- Let'’s go.
We can'’t stay here any longer.
- Follow me.
- Well,
if we meet more slime people,
we'’ll just roll '’em down
the hill. They hate that.
- Look, the Three Spooges!
- All right, porcupine,
you go that way.
- Spinachhead, you head
over to the right there.
- All right, batter up.
Oh, I saw this
on Star Trekonce.
[Imitates monster mumbling]
- Is that your stomach?
- No.
- No, I don'’t want to sing
"The Happy Wanderer" song again.
- Aah!
- Stand here. Take this.
- I'’m going to go down
and screw things up.
- Kind of like fighting
a big, old booger.
- Hey, that was gross, Crow.
- Oh, a vicious, slimy right!
- Oh, man.
He doesn'’t fight fair at all.
I think he just snagged on him.
- All right, fishboy,
this is for you.
- Aah! Aah!
- Nobody messes with our Swedes.
- Hey, that'’s cashmere.
- Stop it.
Stop it!
- Nice tag there.
- Better one, better two.
- Looks more like one
of the first costumes
that didn'’t work out right.
- It'’s angry.
- They'’re trying freeze us
into another wall.
- It'’s the Batmos.
- Whoa,
like popping a zit, boys!
- Oh, no. Does this mean
we have to see clearly
for the rest of the film?
- What?
The fog is lifting.
- We broke the wall.
- It'’s turning back into vapor.
You know,
the machine did control it.
- Come on, you big,
lovable--huh?
- Ew, I kissed the Marine.
- Now that the fog has lifted,
those slime people are about
as scary as Teddy Ruxpin.
- Oh, but that a man might--ugh!
- And now it'’s Bonnie time.
Time to head for the best girl
you can find.
- Are you all right?
- Sure. But look at them.
- A horse! A horse!
My kingdom for a--aah!
- Planes.
- It'’s the jets.
- The wall is gone.
- We can get through now.
Let'’s go.
- Oh, and that'’s
the tanks we get. Heh heh.
- Oh, Bonnie, I got to take off.
These guys might be
looking for me.
A little matter of leaving
the platoon without orders,
you know.
- I'’m glad that'’s over with.
- You know what I'’m going to do
when we get home?
- Huh?
- What'’s that?
- Buy gallons and gallons
of salt
and save it for a foggy day.
- Funny!
- Let'’s hope you never have
to use it again, Bonnie.
- Dad, you don'’t suppose
they could come back?
- I hardly think so.
But who knows?
Perhaps there are other even
stranger creatures underground.
- Thank you, Mr. Optimist.
- Dad, you'’re
being a scientist again.
- Looks like the situation
is well in hand.
- They'’re dropping turkeys.
- Well, Cal,
you'’ve been really worthless,
a coward, and a tower of Jell-O.
Thanks for your help.
- Did you actually break
this wall?
- No, Professor Galbraith did,
Colonel.
- But I was hiding behind him
when he did it.
- The general is waiting
to see you.
We'’ll need a full report.
Will you please come with me?
- With pleasure, sir.
- Well, there goes the last
of the wall, Tom.
- This is just the beginning
for us.
- Brother.
- Come on,
let'’s get out of here.
The love jeep.
- Oh, we better get out of here.
- Hey, Cal, there'’s a bottle of
Jack under the seat.
- You know, Crow, I can always
remember back on earth
the way the house was filled
with the smells
of Mom'’s home cooking.
- You mean your mom would cook
your home?
- Uh, no, Crow,
it'’s just an expression.
It'’s like nothin'’ means lovin'’
like somethin'’ from the oven.
- Ah, yeah, an old expression.
I know one of those.
There as an old man
from Nantucket--
- No, bonk. Sorry.
No, it'’s nothing like that.
Anyway,
I thought it'’d be fun today
to make a silicon diode pie
with a light rectifier crust.
- Oh, you'’re going to put
resistors in it again?
- Yeah. Got some right here.
You don'’t like that--
Anyway, take the resistors,
roll '’em out with a rolling pin.
- Ooh, that makes
the crust crunchy.
- Yeah. Put them in
a special silicon pan.
Heat up your crystal chamber
for 20,000 degrees.
And we'’ll put that in.
And I made one earlier.
I want to show you.
I think I have it right here.
It'’s right here cooling
on the window shade.
Window sill.
- Oh.
- Oh, man.
Gypsy
she ate almost half of it.
- Yeah, and the other half'’s
on her mouth.
- I'’m sorry, Joel.
- You'’re such a messy eater.
Anyway, that'’s okay.
We got a letter to read here.
- Read the one from
Deus Ex Machina.
- Right, good one.
No, this wasn'’t from David.
This is from Sarah McCall
from North Carolina.
She writes,
"Dear MST 3000,Hi, how are you?
"My name is Sarah,
and I'’m 14 years old.
"I love MST 3000.It'’s so good.
Joel is my most favorite person
on the show."
- The only person.
- Yeah, I'’m the only person.
Anyway,
"I love the adlibs they all say.
I'’d watch MST 3000any time
'’til it goes off."
That'’s hopeful.
"Thank whoever made it up.
"Please try to get me an address
where I can write.
Thank you so much.
Sarah McCall."
So we got an address for you.
Crow, you want
to give it to them?
Cambot,
put it up on the screen there.
- The MST 3000Fan Club...
- Well, sirs, that'’s the end
of our experiment.
What do you think?
- Oh, I'’m beside myself. Clay?
- Oh, I'’m thrilled to my marrow.
- I'’m happy. Ow!
- I'’ll file this.
- Yes, do that. Well,
until next time, Team Dream.